http://www.psrc.org/privacy-policy

Skip to main content
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Thank you for visiting the Puget Sound Regional Council website and reviewing our Privacy Policy. This statement addresses collection, use and security of and access to information that may be obtained through use of our website. This notice covers the following topics:
Information Collected and How it is Used
Personal Information and Choice
Public Access to Information
Review and Correction of Personally Identifiable Information
Security
Disclaimer
Contact Information
Information Collected and How it is Used
We will collect no personal information about you when you visit our website unless you choose to give that information to us.
Automatic Collection of Information. If you do nothing during your visit to our website but browse, read pages, or download information, the following information will be automatically collected. This information does not identify you personally. We do not use cookies or any other methods to track individual user visits.
The Internet Protocol (IP) Address and domain name used.
The date and time of each visit.
The web pages and directories visited.
The information we collect automatically is used only to help us understand how our website is being used in order to improve the content and services provided.
Volunteered Information. If, during your visit to our website, you participate in a survey, send an email, or perform some other transaction online, the following additional information will be collected:
The email address and contents of email, including attachments. The information collected is not limited to text and may include any audio, video, and graphic information you send.
Information volunteered in response to a survey.
Information volunteered through an online form for any other purpose.
We use your email information to respond appropriately. This may be to respond to you, to address issues you may identify, to further improve our website or to forward the email for appropriate action. Survey information and information from other online forms is used only for the purpose stated on the requesting web page. We will not sell, rent, or lease your personal information to third parties.
Personal Information and Choice
You may choose whether or not to provide personal information online.
“Personal information” is information about a person that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual’s name, address, and phone number. A domain name or IP address is not considered personal information.
We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us by sending us email, participating in a survey, or completing an online form. You may choose not to contact us by email, participate in a survey or to provide any personal information using an online form. Your choice to not participate in these activities will not impair your ability to browse the Regional Council website, but you may not be able to read or download certain information online. That information will be available if you contact the agency by mail, fax or telephone.
If personal information is requested on the website or volunteered by the user, state law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law.
If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact the Regional Council, as shown in the Contact Information section of this statement.
Users are cautioned that the collection of personal information requested from or volunteered by children online or by email will be treated the same as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public access.
Public Access to Information
In the state of Washington, laws exist to ensure that government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by state government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public’s right to access public records that serve various needs including the privacy of individuals. Exceptions are provided by both state and federal laws.
All of the information collected at this site becomes public records that may be subject to inspection and copying by members of the public, unless an exemption in law exists. RCW 42.56.070(1) states, “Each agency, in accordance with published rules, shall make available for public inspection and copying all public records, unless the record falls within the specific exemptions of subsection (6) of this section, this chapter, or other statute which exempts or prohibits disclosure of specific information or records. To the extent required to prevent an unreasonable invasion of personal privacy interests protected by this chapter, an agency shall delete identifying details in a manner consistent with this chapter when it makes available or publishes any public record; however, in each case, the justification for the deletion shall be explained fully in writing.”
In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Notice and the Public Records Act or other law governing the agency’s disclosure of records, the Public Records Act or other applicable law will control.
Review and Correction of Personally Identifiable Information
You can review any personally identifiable information we collect about you by using the information in the Contact Information section at the end of this notice. You may recommend changes to your personally identifiable information you believe to be inaccurate by submitting an email or written request that credibly shows the inaccuracy. We will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. (RCW 43.105.310)
Security
The Regional Council, as developer and manager of this website, has taken several steps to safeguard the integrity of its data and prevent unauthorized access to information maintained by the Regional Council. These measures are designed and intended to prevent corruption of data, block unknown or unauthorized access to our systems and information, and to provide reasonable protection of private information in our possession.
This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided via the Regional Council website.
Disclaimer
The Regional Council website has links to many other websites operated by government agencies, nonprofit organizations, and private businesses. When you link to another site, you are no longer on the Regional Council website and this Privacy Notice will not apply. When you link to another website, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site.
Neither the Puget Sound Regional Council, nor any officer or employee of the Puget Sound Regional Council warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published by this system, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at their own risk.
Adopted April 25, 2002
Contact Information
To review your personal information, or request correction of your personal information:
To offer comments about the Puget Sound Regional Council website, or about the information presented in this Privacy Policy:
Would you like more information?
